So, are you a victim or a volunteer?
Let's read another excerpt from my latest book,
Body Waving Through the Bullshit, Crank That Through an Essay.
Essay stands for sexual assault.
In the wake of this particular trauma, I came to the shocking realization
that I had a bunch of basic energy, a.k.a. low vibrational people around me.
The only logical reason for this is because
I, too, was operating at a low vibration.
Yeah, I was entertaining friendships that stroked my ego
versus elevating my consciousness or sharpening each other's emotional intelligence.
I was continuing to engage with folks who were consummate capitalists
and still in search of approval and acceptance from them and those systems.
I was still in a committed relationship with a man who let me drive myself home
from the hospital after miscarrying.
That's a whole nother story for a whole nother essay and book.
And though love was an element of the compound,
codependency and trauma bonding were what truly framed the chemical bond.
I may have been a victim of sexual assault,
but I was a volunteer choosing all this.
And in some cases, I didn't even know why.
It would take two more years,
bearing witness to the genocide of the Palestinian people,
a black media smear campaign,
followed by a Zionist smear campaign,
followed by a black Democrat smear campaign,
a divestment from Hollywood and celebrity,
plus a move back east to New York for me to totally untangle myself
from the network of nitwits I'd aligned myself with as my people.
You see, that's the doozy of a trauma.
The trauma is that there's usually a couple more traumas that's going to come along with it.
And sometimes the trauma is just really the shaking up of your whole world
and you having to lean into that.
And that it sucks until you realize that that was the best you could do
with what was given to you
was to alchemize the trauma and horrific experience that you have experienced
into something valuable for evolution,
for the evolving of not only your spirits and your soul,
but of all who are in contact with you,
whether they want to admit it or not.
I had to admit to myself
that the reason I was surrounded by a bunch of low vibrational people
that couldn't support me
was because I had chosen to be around
a bunch of low vibrational people that couldn't support me.
And some might say,
yeah, but Amanda,
you wouldn't have known they couldn't support you
until it was time.
And I would argue that I wasn't even able to identify the aspects of their character
that would let me know if they could support me.
Because that's not the world I was in.
I wasn't in a world that was looking at people and saying,
well, does this person care about things beyond their scope?
Does this person have a curiosity about compassion?
Does this person find capitalism to be incredibly problematic
in the way that it disconnects us
from everything that is supposed to make us good people?
I didn't have the insight to even be that investigative.
And I'm not joking when I say I had to go through all of those different things
to bring me closer and closer and closer and closer.
And I'm still moving closer
to being able to see.
And I am surrounded by folks now
that exist in their entire lives
in showing compassion and love.
And not just career-wise,
because I know a lot of showing compassion and love folks
that are in the movement
that when it's time for you to need compassion and love,
they ain't got shit for you.
They love to go out there and hold up signs
and get arrested,
but don't let you get sick.
They don't got time for you.
So, again, it's, of course, a mixed bag, you know?
And it's, of course, a matter of trial and error.
However, I have found that the closer I have gotten
to centering and continuing to cultivate
my own humanity and care,
the better I've become at surrounding myself
with those who do the same
for not only themselves,
but for the people who are around them.
Oh, Jordy, you're so high vibrational.
Body Waving Through the BS,
Crank That Through an Essay,
is available only at amandalandexports.com.
I hope that you will support this work.
And I hope that you will allow it
to help you be supported in, unfortunately,
your own experience with essay
or in supporting those around you
who have experienced this.
Thank you for supporting my little shop.